Are you ready for the truth?
Unbreakable is a thriller, drama, mystery film directed by M. Night Shyamalan.
An ordinary man makes an extraordinary discovery when a train accident
leaves his fellow passengers dead — and him unscathed.
The answer to this mystery could lie with the mysterious Elijah Price, a man who
suffers from a disease that renders his bones as fragile as glass.
David Dunn, played by Bruce Willis.
Elijah Price, played by Samuel L. Jackson.
Audrey Dunn, played by Robin Wright.
Joseph Dunn, played by Spencer Treat Clark.
Elijah's Mother, played by Charlayne Woodard.
Dr. Mathison, played by Eamonn Walker.
Unbreakable is a 2000 American superhero thriller film
written, produced, and directed by M.
Night Shyamalan, and starring Bruce Willis, Samuel L.
Jackson, and Robin Wright.
In Unbreakable, David Dunn (Willis) survives a train crash with no injuries,
leading to the realization that he harbors superhuman abilities.
As he begins to grapple with this discovery, he comes to the attention of disabled comic book
store owner Elijah Price (Jackson), who manipulates David to understand him.
Shyamalan organized the narrative of Unbreakable to parallel a
comic book's traditional three-part story structure.
After settling on the origin story, Shyamalan wrote the screenplay as a speculative screenplay with
Willis already set to star in the film and Jackson in mind to portray Elijah Price.
Filming began in April 2000 and was completed in July.
Unbreakable was released on November 22, 2000.
It received generally positive reviews, with praise for Shyamalan's direction, screenplay, its aesthetics, the
performances, the emotional weight of the story, cinematography, and the score by James Newton Howard.
The film has subsequently gained a strong cult following.
A realistic vision of the superhero genre, it is regarded by many as one of
Shyamalan's best films and one of the best superhero films.
In 2011, Time listed it as one of the top ten superhero
films of all time, ranking it number four.
Quentin Tarantino also included it on his list of the
top 20 films released from 1992 to 2009.
After years of development on a follow-up film, a thematic sequel, Split, with Willis
reprising his role as David Dunn in a cameo role, was released in January 2017.
After the financial and critical success of Split, Shyamalan immediately began working on a third film, titled Glass, which
was released January 18, 2019, thus making Unbreakable the first installment in the Unbreakable film series.
The film explores themes of philadelphia, pennsylvania, parent child
relationship, marriage crisis, superhero, train accident.
The tone is mind_bending and emotional and intense.